export const questions
 = [
  {
    question: "What is ReactJS primarily used for?",
    options: [
      "Server-side scripting",
      "Front-end web development",
      "Database management",
      "Mobile app development",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a core concept of React?",
    options: ["Components", "Props", "State", "Loops"],
    correctAnswer: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "In React, what does JSX stand for?",
    options: [
      "JavaScript XML",
      "JavaScript Extension",
      "JavaScript Execute",
      "JavaScript XHR",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 0, 
  },
  {
    question: "What is the main purpose of the 'ReactDOM' library in React?",
    options: [
      "To handle routing in React applications",
      "To manage component state",
      "To render React components into the DOM",
      "To create reusable components",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
  {
    question:
      "In React, which method is called once a class component is mounted to the DOM?",
    options: [
      "componentDidMount",
      "componentDidUpdate",
      "componentWillUnmount",
      "componentWillMount",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 0, 
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of the 'props' object in React components?",
    options: [
      "It holds the component's internal state.",
      "It represents the parent component's data passed to the child component.",
      "It handles asynchronous operations.",
      "It defines the component's styles.",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1, 
  },
  {
    question: "In React, what is the purpose of the 'setState' method?",
    options: [
      "To update the component's state",
      "To define the component's initial state",
      "To render child components",
      "To fetch data from an API",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 0, 
  },
  {
    question: "What is the virtual DOM in React?",
    options: [
      "A browser extension for debugging React apps",
      "A lightweight DOM used for server-side rendering",
      "A representation of the actual DOM in memory",
      "A component for creating virtual user interfaces",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which React hook is used to perform side effects in a functional component?",
    options: ["useState", "useEffect", "useContext", "useMemo"],
    correctAnswer: 1, 
  },
  {
    question: "What is Redux used for in a React application?",
    options: [
      "Styling and layout",
      "Routing",
      "State management",
      "API requests",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
  {
    question: "In React, what does the term 'unidirectional data flow' mean?",
    options: [
      "Data can flow in both directions between components.",
      "Data flows only from parent to child components.",
      "Data flows only from child to parent components.",
      "Data flows randomly between components.",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 1, 
  },
  {
    question: "Which method is used to handle user input in React forms?",
    options: ["onChange", "onSubmit", "onInput", "onClick"],
    correctAnswer: 0, 
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of React Router in a React application?",
    options: [
      "To manage state",
      "To create components",
      "To handle routing and navigation",
      "To perform API requests",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool can you use for debugging React applications?",
    options: [
      "Redux",
      "React Inspector",
      "Chrome Developer Tools",
      "Visual Studio Code",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the primary advantage of using a state management library like MobX or Redux in a React application?",
    options: [
      "It reduces the need for components.",
      "It simplifies the build process.",
      "It centralizes and manages application state.",
      "It improves the performance of rendering.",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 2, 
  },
];
